NARRATOR: Meet John,
a software developer.
John develops a
program, and now he
realizes the program is
surrounded by a lot of bugs.
John starts
exploring a solution.
He surfs through the internet,
checks programmer communities.
Doubting every step
of the way, John
feels his problem is not solved.
Desperate to find the solution,
John meets his friend Adam.
Adam comes up with an
idea of an artificially
intelligent and practical
solution called the ChatGPT.
Adam says ChatGPT
has the caliber
to systematically
resolve all the bugs
with an elaborate explanation
for every step it makes.
ChatGPT is an
AI-trained model that
works in a conversational
way, developed by OpenAI.
Fascinated by hearing
this, John asks
Adam to explain him in detail.
After Adam explains
that, GPT a.k.a.
generative pre-training
transformer,
has come a long way.
Before the introduction of GPT,
natural language processing
used to deal with a specific
task with large amounts of data.
GPT was first released
in 2018, which contained
117 million parameters.
GPT, GPT-2, and GPT-3,
each one is stronger
than the one before it.
The main reason why GPT
received little attention
was that it was more of an idea
or test than a finished product.
But after the
introduction of GPT-2,
it gained a lot of attention,
as it could accurately
predict the word that
would begin a text.
Then they introduced GPT-3,
which is a strong language
model, achieving translation,
question-answering,
and performing
three-digit arithmetic.
But ChatGPT stands tall compared
to all other achievements
of OpenAI.
So how does it work?
ChatGPT uses deep
learning techniques
to generate human-like text.
It is based on the
machine learning
model derived from the class
called, the large language
model.
ChatGPT is a byproduct
of InstructGPT.
InstructGPT
introduced a strategy
for integrating human feedback
into the training process
to match model outputs.
This innovative technology
made ChatGPT exceptional.
It is trained on the
massive data sets of text
from the internet and
learns from the patterns
and relationships between
words and phrases.
It responds to a prompt by
determining the next word based
on the context, then
repeats the process
until a stop condition is met.
As a result, ChatGPT can produce
various logical responses
to various queries and prompts.
The most important
components of ChatGPT
are the transformer
model and language model.
Coming to the
transformer model, it
is a neural network
architecture designed
to process sequential data.
It consists of multiple
layers of self-attention
and a feedforward network.
After the transformer model
has processed the input,
a decoder generates the output.
The decoder uses the context
provided by the encoder
to generate the response.
The model is trained using
unsupervised learning
and fine-tuned on specific
tasks using supervised learning.
For successful
completion of tasks,
it needs pre-trained data.
The model first
encodes the input text,
then converts it to a
numerical representation,
which can be processed by
the model's neural network.
This encoding is done using
the embedded layer that
maps the work.
Then comes the language model.
ChatGPT is trained as a
language model, trained
to predict the next
word in a sequence given
the previous words.
The language model intends to
produce rational, consistent.
And meaningful output.
The pre-trained ChatGPT can
be tuned for a specific task.
So ChatGPT passes
a fine-tuning test
by answering questions,
generating text summaries,
or generating text in
response to a query.
Overall, ChatGPT is a
powerful language model
with a combination
of techniques.
Like deep learning, machine
learning, neural networks,
and natural language processing.
Can ChatGPT change
a wide variety
of business tasks, John asked?
ChatGPT possesses the ability
to automate content creation
on social media, create
chatbot and e-commerce sites,
provide medical assistance by
acting as a symptom checker,
write code and
assist a developer.
Thus, ChatGPT can change the
working of every industry.
Now, John can resolve
any coding issue
without looking into
any other resources.
But like any other
technology, ChatGPT
comes with a few limitations
that can be its Achilles heel.
ChatGPT is capable of
developing content up to 2021.
It finds difficulty in
providing logical reasoning
in certain situations.
And also, ChatGPT lags in
translation, summarization,
and sometimes
question-answering.
But above all, ChatGPT has
shown remarkable ability
by providing accurate answers
flawlessly in a creative way
in very short periods of time.
But before we end, I
have a question for you.
Which language model
does ChatGPT belong to?
1, GPT-3.
2, GPT-4.
3, GPT-2.
4, GPT.
Give the answer with
reasoning and stand a chance
to win an Amazon voucher.
Think about it and leave the
answer in the comment section,
and we will provide the
answer in the next week.
We hope you enjoyed this video.
If you did, a thumbs up
would be really appreciated.
Here's your reminder to
subscribe to our channel
and click on the bell icon for
more on the latest technologies
and trends.
Thank you for watching and stay
tuned for more from Simplilearn.
[MUSIC PLAYING]